

#### TECH / SKILLS

HTML **UX DESIGN** CSS **UI DESIGN BOOTSTRAP** WIRE-FRAMING **JAVASCRIPT PROTOTYPING JQUERY USER RESEARCH** REACT MOCK UPS **EXPRESS GRAPHIC DESIGN NODEJS PHOTOGRAPHY NEXTJS IMAGE EDITING MONGODB** GIT/GITHUB

HEROKU

#### **SOFTWARE**

WORDPRESS

**VS CODE PHOTOSHOP BOOTSTRAP STUDIO** LIGHTROOM AXURF RP **ILLUSTRATOR** MS OFFICE ADOBE XD

# **SOFT SKILLS**

**CRITICAL THINKING AUTHENTICITY** COMMUNICATION TIME MANAGEMENT **FAST LEARNER** RELIABILITY **DETAIL ORIENTATED** INDEPENDANT

# **PERSONAL**

Birthday : 11 April 1994

South African & Greek Nationality

Languages : English

### CONTACT



Cape Town, South Africa



+27 84 413 5465



nikitabatlis@live.com



https://nikitabatlis.github.io/portfolio/

# NIKITA BATLIS

# Web Developer

#### **PROFILE**

I thrive on creative front-end challenges and enjoy implementing UI trends into my current projects. I have a particular interest in accessible UX design and believe the key to a product's long-term success is putting the user's experience first.

I spent 4 years working on yachts and in hospitality, before returning home to continue my education and transition to a career in full MERN stack Web Development and UX/UI design. Having completed my boot-camp and diploma, I am looking for a graduate/junior position within a strong team to further my industry knowledge.

Equipped with a conscientious work ethic - I am a reliable, proactive colleague with a keen eye for detail, and will never skip an opportunity to learn something new.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP**

HYPERIONDEV, CAPE TOWN

A full MERN stack web development course that taught me to build dynamic, data-driven web applications with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Express & React.

2020

# **BRAND & MARKETING MANAGEMENT**

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Part time 6 month course to develop both theoretical and practical knowledge in the field of brand building and digital marketing.

## PROFESSIONAL DIPLOMA IN UX DESIGN

UX DESIGN INSTITUTE, IRELAND

Correspondence 1 year diploma in professional UX design user theory, research methods, prototyping and wireframing work-flows, as well as design thinking and analysis.

2019 - 2020

# CERTIFICATE IN COMMERCIAL **PHOTOGRAPHY**

VEGA SCHOOL, CAPE TOWN

Full time 2 year certification in professional photography, image editing and manipulation, as well as graphic design.

2013 - 2014

# JOB HISTORY

# Photographer & Worpress Designer

Apr 2019 - Present

Freelance Student | Cape Town

Commissioned portraiture, location and real estate photography. As well as specialized Wordpress website designs for small local businesses.

#### Location Scout & Researcher

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

Cape Town Productions | www.ctprod.co.za | Cape Town

A summer contract managing and updating the company's location database while researching and scouting new locations around Cape Town. Along with assisting on set and in-office coordinators.

#### Stewardess

Dec 2017 - Sep 2018

Katara | 123m Private Motor Yacht | Spain

Working & living closely with a team of 70 multinationals. Managing & maintaining luxury yacht interiors while delivering 10 Star service for Arab Royalty.

### **Junior Stewardess**

Apr 2017 - Sep 2017

Lady Nag Nag | 53m Motor Yacht | France & Monaco

Seasonal contract on board a demanding, fast pased privately owned yacht.

#### **REFERENCES**

Gavin Hartford Stakeholder Solutions +27 82 903 1725 gavin@stakeholdersolutions.co.za Gabi Lowe Upfront Marketing & The Coaching Nest +27 83 455 4774 gabi@thecoachingnest.co.za